Tomasz Ciborski

Nationality: Polish

Date of birth: 15th April 1991 Mobile: +48 796 666 678 Email: tomasz@ciborski.com

Marital status: single

Place of residence: Poland, Wrocław

Personal summary:

I am a 28-year-old professional, with 10 years of programming and tech experience. I am looking for opportunities to solve today's world problems using modern techniques. I would like to work in a team of strongly focused professionals or build one from scratch. I am particularly interested in designing and implementing reliable and scalable systems using proven and well known technologies. I believe in the approach of using simple blocks to compose a complex system. I am mobile and happy to relocate.

Areas of competence:

My experience ranges from building basic blocks of SaaS company to operations on C-level in a mid-sized business. My tech skill set covers linux server administration, NoSQL databases, programming in today's most popular frameworks and team management. I am a big promoter of SaaS model, SCRUM methodology, iterative approach, SOLID, KISS, DRY, YAGNI, divide and conquer and functional programming. I also had multiple opportunities to work with enterprise regulation requirements such as GDPR and others.

Experience:

Heraldbee – Jan 2019 – now – https://heraldbee.com/

Full-stack programming, later, team building for a SaaS startup to drive sales for small to medium e-commerce shops such as Shopify or WooCommerce.

TimeCamp – Sept 2014 – Oct 2018 – https://www.timecamp.com/

I scaled the company SaaS wise and technology-wise from 50 paying companies to over 2000 in 4 years. I took major part in team assembly, training and nurturing. At peak, I was managing 2 SCRUM teams of 6 people each. TimeCamp went through major reorganization due to my input. The company is going to IPO in 2019.

Tech: PHP, Codelgniter, MySQL, Angular 1, nginx, docker and others

HeySpace - R&D project in TimeCamp, https://hey.space/

I am the inventor behind the idea of combining Trello and Slack. I Assembled the team and delivered the project within 2 months. It Has 200 daily online users at peak and is steadily rising.

Tech: React, Redux, Node, docker and others

TimeCamp 3 – failed rewrite of TimeCamp to highly scalable architecture
The project failed because of constant requirement changes, inflated scalability
requirements and lack of proper project management. I learned on what not to
do when rewriting large codebases. The project also showed me how poor
management may lead to never–ending development and "CV–building".
Tech: NoSQL, Couchbase, Sync Gateway, PouchDb, Blip, PHP, docker–swarm

Other projects:

- Author of NextPage Chrome Extension 2019
- ESCP university masters tutor 2018
- I created Student Attendance Monitoring System for University of Manchester; School of Materials Raspberry PI, C#, electronics 2015
- The Blackboard Crawler Python script which crawls the University of Manchester's student portal and downloads all course materials to disk – 2012
- <u>Web aplication</u> (ASP.NET MVC), pivot table report generator (Excel interop, WPF) and Haematology Calculator for Santelab medical laboratory 2013
- batch Excel spreadsheets loader and Excel Add–In (C#, Windows Forms, Excel interop) and Pre–ETL client – server application for Value Based Advisors – 2012

Education:

University of Manchester, UK – 2011 to 2015 – Electrical and Electronic Engineering – BEng with honors

Wroclaw University of Technology, PL – 2010 to 2011 – Computer Science – dropped out

Tag list: ASP.NET, AWS EC2, Apache CouchDB, BeautifulSoup, C#, Couchbase, DBase, DNS, Debian, Django, Firebase, Google APIs, IIS, Labview, MS SQL, MVC, MariaDb, MiFare, MongoDB, MultiSim, MySQL, OpenWrt, PostgreSQL, PouchDb, RFID, Raspberry Pi, React, React, Redis, Redux, RegExp, Reverse Engineering, SQLCompact, SQLite, SSL certificates, SolidWorks, Ubuntu, Visual Studio, Vultr, Wordpress, agile, ansible, apache thrift, applescript, bash, beanstalkd, blip, bootstrap, collectd, cygwin, dBASE, dnsmasq, docker, docker–compose, docker–swarm, grafana, ip, iptables, jQuery, jekyll, jenkins, kernel compilation, let's encrypt, libfreefare, linux, macOS, mailserver, nginx, nmap, ollydbg, openvpn, oxyplot, pandas, product owner, rattic, route, routing, scrum, sequelize, ssh, sshfs, vim, vnc, vps, windows